Mohamed Mahmoud El-Sharkawi

SAP Project Manager – Technical Architect

Certified PMP, SAP Activate, SAP Design Thinking, SAP Analytics, SAP HANA

Notice Period 2-4 Weeks

Mobile: +201556139067 Mobile: +201117770527

E-Mail: sharkawi.sap@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-mahmoud-el-sharkawi-60428822/ SAP Certificates: https://www.credly.com/users/mohamed-mahmoud-el-sharkawi/badges

PMI-PMP: https://www.credly.com/users/mohamed-mahmoud.c6d73c5f/badges

References: Anwar Rafat (+201004492621) Anwar- Group CTO at IGI Holding-

Email: anwar.raafat@gmail.com

Hossam Elbarmawy (+201117770511) - ECS IT Director

Email: hossam.elbarmawy@ecs-co.com

Summary

SAP Projects Manager, Application Manager, and Service Delivery Manager, for the last 15 Years of Experience in SAP solutions implementation, and support.

Following SAP Activate Implementation Methodology (Prepare-Explore-Realize-Deploy) Waterfall and agile, deploy, implement, and support Implementation with Solution Manager repository and project management for Process Design, Documentation, and testing plans execution.

With Technical and functional experience, Project management Skills, Proactive, self-motivated, reliable for monitoring issues logs and problems, communicating with the project team and stakeholders for business value realization, delivery progress status, and feedback.

E2E Experience in SAP Products projects delivery for SAP ECC 6, and SAP S4hana functional business process (FI, CO, MM, SD, PM, PP, Retail, Public Sector), plus Technical deployment HA and DR, supporting organizations define the low-level and high-level technical and functional solutions and architecture, building integration between on-premises and cloud solutions to realize the business value from a secure digital transformation.

Manage IT governance, Policies, and security, supporting periodic internal, and external Audit controls to fulfill external audit requirements KPMG, PWC, and EY.

Managing projects and organizations' business solutions, operation handover, data center infrastructure integration, and security of sap services.

Experience in healthcare business solutions implementation, and integration with SAP ERP, medical devices integration with middleware, Hospital Management Systems, Applications Development, and Innovation.

Experience:

Enterprise Consulting Services – ECS-CO.COM July 2022– Present

Senior SAP Project Manager, HANA and Digital Transformation

Manage SAP Product Implementation, integration, Upgrade, and Migration Projects – Business Process integration, Support Basis and technical Integration in All other Projects.

Enterprise Consulting Services – ECS-CO.COM June 2019 – Present SAP Project Manager, HANA and Digital Transformation

Manage SAP Product Implementation, integration, Upgrade, and Migration Projects – Business Process integration, Support Basis and technical Integration in All other Projects.

Responsibilities:

- Lead customer stakeholders and project team delivering and supporting the smooth transformation of business needs to project outcomes, deliverables, and value by planning, executing, monitoring, and controlling project communication, phases, activities, and deliverables for closure.
- Responsible for directing the project team.
- taking ownership and responsibility for project delivery, project planning, control, and customer satisfaction.
- Manage communications with the customer team and consultant team, facilitate and coordinate for stakeholder engagement.
- regularly communicate and share stakeholder feedback for value realized, issues, and risks, and updates for project status.
- Manage Project budget waterfall, and agile
- Managing quality assurance and timeliness of Activities and project team activities
- Change Management and scope monitoring and control

Projects in ECS (Project Manager):

- March 2022- SAP S4HANA Core Implementation in Public Sector Currently in progress.
- July 2021- SAP S4HANA FMCG Implementation Remotely
- March 2020- SAP S4HANA implementation and re-engineering with the integration of SRM, SAP Commerce, SAP Success factors, JDA WMS, Jaggaer Blue Younder, and data migration from ECC in
- Jan 2020- SAP S4hana Retail (Retail, CAR, POS GK-Opentext), Sap cloud marketing and services implementation and integration
- 2019- SAP success factors EC Integration with ERP HCM working with Deloitte in global SSF implementation –
- 2019- ERP, SCM, BW OS/DB Migration to SAP Suite on HANA, SCM on HANA, and BW on Hana
- **2019** SAP Backbone 2020 Implementation (Solman 7.2 Upgrade, and New Installations) for ECS Customers

Integrated Diagnostics Holdings – IDHCORP.COM January 2012 – June-2019 SAP Service Delivery Manager

Manage all IDH subsidiaries Healthcare Solutions, SAP ERP ECC 6.0 Implementation, Conversion to S4hana, SAP S4hana integration, SAP Successfactors, and SAP Cloud Platforms Integration, HANA Database Administration, Modeling, and Data Integration

Projects in IDH (Project Manager):

- 2019- SAP S4HANA **Remote** Implementation in Techno lab
- 2019- SAP S4HANA Implementation in Megalab
- 2019- SAP S4HANA IFRS 16 Real State (Lease) in IDH Subsidiaries
- 2018- SAP S4HANA Datacenter Migration and DR site replication
- 2018 SAP S4HANA Advanced Cash Management
- 2018- SAP S4HANA Integration with LIMS Sales
- 2017- SAP S4HANA 1709 FPS01, FPS02, ECC Conversion and Upgrade
- 2016- SAP HANA 1.0, 2.0 Migration
- 2016- SAP Lenovo Appliance Upgrade + HANA 2 SPS03 Rev33 Upgrade

IDH - Almokhtabar Laboratories April 2004 - January 2012

IT Infrastructure and Operation Manager

- IT Infrastructure and Data Centers management
- IT Operation management, follow up and monitor IT service performance and improve IT services.
- Healthcare Service Improvement and Aligning Information Technology vision- Infrastructure, IT Projects, Vendors and Partner Service level management.
- Governance and IT policies development and management.
- Do training and performance improvement for IT staff.

Infrastructure and Solutions Projects:

- SAP ERP in IDH subsidiaries (Alborg- Almokhtabar)
- SAP BPC Consolidation Almokhtabar Group
- SAP Solution manager 7.2
- Upgrade Datacenter (Microsoft, CISCO LAN, WAN, VPN, Security)
- Citrix XenAPP, and Virtual XenServer Implementation
- VMware and MS HyperV Implementation
- Security Implementation Cisco ASA, Juniper firewalls, Fortigate Firewall, WAF
- Lab information System-Automation LIS
- Alborg and Almokhtabar Datacenter Design, Implementation and integration
- Implementation in Sudan, KSA (Solutions + Infrastructure)
- HRMIS HR system
- New IDH Datacenter (Infrastructure, Security, Backup, High availability and other infrastructure Services)

Orascom Technology Solutions January 2003 - April 2004

Trainer

Delivering training phase in projects for IT technologies (power builder 7, oracle developer 6/6i/, Sybase adaptive server Enterprise)

Compulink February 2001 - July 2002

Power Builder programmer in Hospital Information System, developing Data window reports, for outpatient module

Education:

Certified PMP Project Management Professional Certified 2022 MBA in progress Cardiff Metropolitan University 2022 Project Management Diploma Project Management 2012

Helwan University Cairo

Faculty of computers and Information Systems, Major Information System · (1996 - 2000)

SAP Certifications:

- C_SAC_2002 SAP Certified Application Associate SAP Analytics Cloud
- C THINK 01 SAP Certified Associate Design Thinking
- C_HANATEC_13 SAP Certified Technology Associate SAP HANA 2.0 (SPS00)
- C_ACTIVATE_5 SAP Certified Project Manager

Courses:

- o PMP, SAP Agile, ITIL Foundations 3 and 4, TOGAF 9.2
- o SAP Basis, ABAP, FI, MM, HCM, Terp10
- o PFA Professional Financial Accountant
- o Oracle9i DBA, Oracle6i Dev, Sybase Power Builder
- o CCNA, MCSE, Linux SUSE

OpenSAP Record of Achievements:

- o Digital Transformation Track
- o System Conversion to SAP S/4HANA (s4h11)
- o Software Development on SAP HANA (Update Q4/2017) (hana6)
- o SAP HANA Data Management Suite Strategy Talk (hdms1)
- SAP Leonardo IoT for the Intelligent Enterprise (leo2)
- o SAP Leonardo Machine Learning Foundation An Introduction (leo5)
- o SAP Leonardo Enabling the Intelligent Enterprise (leo1)

OpenSAP Confirmation of Participation:

o Leadership in Digital Transformation (ldt1-tl)